Neil V. Rosenberg bluegrass music collection
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
- Series 3: Sound recordings, Digital files are located in afc2002009_dc001. Please see the AFC reference staff for access.
  - Oberlin Folk Singers recorded at WOBC by Al Gourevitch and Neil V. Rosenberg (reel 2 of 2), March 25, 1958, AFC 2002/009: SR021; 1 sound tape reel (acetate, Side 1: 00:32:41, Side 2: 00:32:35): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in.
    - "Hard Traveling" - Neil Rosenberg
      Neil Rosenberg, guitar and vocal; Mayne Smith, harmonica
    - "Noah's Dove" - Mayne Smith
    - "Flavor in My Cream" - Neil Rosenberg
      Neil Rosenberg, guitar and vocal; Mayne Smith, banjo
    - "He Never Said a Mumblin' Word" - Mayne Smith and Neil Rosenberg
      Neil Rosenberg, guitar and vocal; Mayne Smith, banjo and vocal
    - "Take a Whiff On Me" - Mayne Smith and Neil Rosenberg
    - Spoof interview of a folksong scholar
      The voices may be Al Gourevitch and Franklin Miller. Further notes regarding the spoof interview are on the accompanying documentation.
  - Flatt and Scruggs radio dubs, circa 1954, AFC 2002/009: SR022; Marvin Hedrick; RXI 0141; 1 sound tape reel (Side 1: 00:31:24, Side 2: 00:26:00): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in.
    Radio dubs made by Marvin Hedrick, from WRVA and WSM.
    - Side 1
      - "I'm Going to Make Heaven My Home"
      - "Billy In The Low Ground"
      - "Why Don't You Tell Me So"
      - "So Happy I'll Be (Going Home)"
      - "Black Eyed Susie"
      - "Dear Old Dixie"
      - "Cabin in Caroline"
      - "Cotton Eyed Joe"
      - "Roll in My Sweet Baby's Arms"
      - "I'm Working On A Road"
      - "Salty Dog"
      - "I'm Waiting To Hear You Call Me Darling"
      - "I'm Getting Ready To Go"
      - "I'll Never Love Another"
      - "Listen to the Mocking Bird"
      - "Down The Road"
      - "Somebody Else Will"
    - Side 2
      - "Reuben"
      - "Randy Lynn Rag"
      - "Bubblin' In My Soul"
      - "Rock of Ages"
      - "No Room"
      - "Wait A Little Longer, Please Jesus"
      - "Little Maggie"
      - "Someday We'll Meet Again, Sweetheart"
  - Rolf Cahn flamenco program (KPFA), circa 1962-1966, AFC 2002/009: SR023; 1 sound tape reel (acetate, Side 1: 00:36:49, Side 2: 00:26:22): analog, 7 1/2 ips, full track and half track, mono; 7 in.
  - Neil V. Rosenberg and Scott Hambly on the Billy Faier show; Janet Smith, AFC 2002/009: SR025
    - Sound recording, RXI 0142; 1 sound tape reel (Side 1: 00:32:18, Side 2: 00:32:29): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in.
      - Side 1
        - Neil V. Rosenberg and Scott Hambly on the Billy Faier show, KPFA, Berkeley, CA, March 25, 1958
          "Story of Folk Music" (show title). Faier's interview of Rosenberg and Hambly is interspersed with live performances of songs. Both Rosenberg and Hambly play guitars.
          According to Rosenberg, the Billy Faier show recording is probably a master.
          - Introduction by Billy Faier
          - "Backwater Blues" [Neil]
          - Discussion
          - "Key to the Highway" [Neil]
          - Discussion
          - "Cherry Red" [Scott]
            There is a 22-second gap in the interview segment.
          - Discussion
          - "Acres of Clams" [Neil]
          - "Death Letter Blues" [Neil]
          - "Shorty George" [Neil]
          - Discussion and show outro
          - Neil V. Rosenberg and Charles Crawford, parody "field recording," Oberlin, 1958
            According to the documentation, this is a "parody Interview with Mr. Fuggs by Mr. X of the Gumps Folk Institute."
      - Side 2
        - Home demo - Janet Smith, 1958
          Archivist's note: Mayne Smith and Janet Smith are brother and sister.
          According to Rosenberg this tape is probably a copy.
          - "The Water Is Wide"
          - "The Unquiet Grave"
          - "Babe, I'm Gonna Leave You"
          - "I Once Loved A Lass"
          - "McPhee's Farewell"
          - "Scarborough Fair"
          - "To Phoebe"
          - "Every Night When the Sun Goes In"
          - "Old Lord By The Northern Sea (Twa Sisters)"
          - "Binnorie"
          - "Woe To The Heart"
            The tape runs out before the song is finished.
    - Documentation
      - Song list and production notes for SR025, April 12, 2011, nvrsh1958-06-00.txt; 1 manuscript; black and white, digital (.txt)
      - Janet Smith: home demo, 1958, April 12, 2011, js1958demo.txt; 1 manuscript; black and white, digital (.txt)
      - Janet Smith: original tape box interior for the home demo, 1958, js1958demo_Reel 25_.pdf; 1 manuscript; color, digital (.pdf)
  - Mark Spoelstra; Rolf Cahn, circa July-August 1960, AFC 2002/009: SR026; 1 sound tape reel (acetate, Side 1: 00:26:42, Side 2: 00:26:33): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in.
    - Mark Spoelstra
      - "Nine Pound Hammer"
      - "It's Your Misfortune"
      - "Salty Dog"
      - "Easy Rider"
      - "Hard-R--- Blues"
      - "Woman's Lover"
      - "Walk the Muddy Water"
      - "Train"
    - Rolf Cahn
      No accompanying documentation.
  - Mac Wiseman, AFC 2002/009: SR027; Marvin Hedrick; RXH 8875; 1 sound tape reel (Side 1: 00:32:15, Side 2: 00:42:48): analog, 7 1/2 and 3 3/4 ips, half track, mono; 7 in.
    Continued on SR081.
    - Side 1
      - Mac Wiseman radio dubs, circa 1954
        Recorded from WRVA radio, Richmond, Virginia.
        - "Don't Let Your Sweet Love Die"
        - "Sweeter Than the Honey"
        - "Steel Guitar"
        - "I Don't Love Nobody"
        - "Buffalo Girls"
          On dobro
        - "There's A Bluebird Singing"
        - "Fire On The Mountain"
        - "Long Journey Home"
        - "Little Home in Tennessee"
        - "Bill Cheatham"
        - "Pig In A Pen"
        - "Don't Blame It On Me"
        - "Remembering"
          From a record
      - Mac Wiseman, with a band including Allen Shelton, November 28, 1953
        Radio broadcast, recorded from WRVA, Richmond, Virginia. Continued on Side 2.
        - "Rainbow in the Valley"
        - "Sunny Mountain Chimes"
        - "When It's Reveille Time in Heaven"
        - "I Got The Crazy Blues"
        - "Two O'clock"
    - Side 2
      - Mac Wiseman, with a band including Allen Shelton, November 28, 1953
        Continued from Side 1. End of the show.
        - "Four Walls Around" - Allen Shelton
      - WOBC radio broadcast, Oberlin, Ohio, circa 1958-1959
        Personnel: Chuck Crawford, banjo; Frank Miller, guitar; Neil Rosenberg, mandolin; Rickey Sherover, banjo; Phil Specht, washtub bass.
      - Mac Wiseman at Bean Blossom, Indiana, circa 1954
        - "Dance All Night"
        - unidentified song
        - "Old Joe Clark"
        - "Wildfire"
        - "Shackles and Chains"
        - "Train 45"
        - "Courtin' in the Rain"
        - "Alimony"
        - "Golden Slippers"
        - "I Haven't Got The Right"
  - Brownie and Sonny LP / Angola Prison Songs LP, AFC 2002/009: SR028; 1 sound tape reel (polyester, Side 1: 00:35:32, Side 2: 00:37:20): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in.
    Brownie McGhee and Sonny Terry. Documentation with the recording points to Blues Unlimited no. 82, page 25, for the table of contents; this is for the prison LP only. The tape includes dubs of one and possibly two albums. The list of contents is conjectural until the tape is digitized and songs (and sources) confirmed.
    - Brownie and Sonny LP, undated
      An unidentified LP
    - Angola Prisoners' Blues (LP), 1959
      - Levee Camp Blues - Robert Pete Williams
      - Stagolee - Hogman Maxey
      - Electric Chair Blues - Guitar Welch
      - Prisoner's Talking Blues - Robert Pete Williams
      - Motherless Children Have A Hard Time - Robert Pete Williams
      - Black Night Fallin' - Hogman Maxey
      - Some Got Six Months - Robert Pete Williams
      - I'm Gonna Leave You Mama - Guitar Welch
      - I'm Lonesome Blues - Robert Pete Williams
  - Jim and Jesse and the Virginia Boys; Carl Story; McCormick Brothers; Cousin Emmy; Pete Steele, March 29, 1938, 1958, AFC 2002/009: SR029; Irwin Nash; 1 sound tape reel (acetate, Side 1: 00:32:29, Side 2: 00:32:14): analog, 3 3/4 ips, half track, mono; 5 in.
    - Side 1
      Recordings of Jim and Jesse were copied from WEAR-TV, Pensacola, Florida.
      - Jim and Jesse and the Virginia Boys, circa 1956-1958
        - "Wheel Hoss"
        - "Banjolina"
        - "Cotton-Eyed Joe"
        - "Bill Cheatham"
        - "Hamilton County Breakdown"
        - "Red Wing"
        - "Smokey Mountain Rag"
        - "Cripple Creek"
          Includes a fragment of another tune
        - "Cumberland Gap"
        - "Fire on the Mountain"
        - "Rainbow"
        - "Jingle Bells"
        - "Back Up and Four" [possibly "Back Up And Push"]
        - "Shucking Corn"
        - "Katie Hill"
        - "Fire on the Banjo"
        - "Under the Double Eagle"
        - "John Henry"
      - "Mocking Banjo" - Carl Story
        The recording was released on the Mercury record label.
      - "Haskel's Five String" - McCormick Brothers
        The recording was released on the Hickory Records label.
      - "Banjo on the Mountain" - Carl Story
    - Side 2
      - Kentucky Mountain Ballads - Cousin Emmy, 1947
        Decca A-574
        - "Come All You Virginia Girls"
        - "Pretty Little Miss Out in the Garden"
        - "I Wish I Was in Bowling Green"
        - "Johnny Booker"
        - "I Wish I Was a Single Girl Again"
        - "Lost John"
        - "Free Little Bird"
      - Pete Steele, March 29, 1938
        The Pete Steele recordings were copied from field recordings in the Alan Lomax Ohio and Indiana collection (AFC 1938/004).
        - "Cripple Creek"
          AFC 1938/004: AFS 01710 B2
        - "John Henry"
          AFC 1938/004: AFS 01711 A2. Steel plays the guitar.
        - "Darling Cora"
          AFC 1938/004: AFS 01712 B
        - "Weary Blues"
          AFC 1938/004: AFS 01712 A
  - Anthology of country and bluegrass singles, AFC 2002/009: SR030; 1 sound tape reel (polyester; Side 1: 01:02:13, Side 2: 00:58:00): analog, 3 3/4 and 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in.
    Digitization note: there are a few changes in speed over the course of both tape sides.
    - Side 1
      - Wildwood Flower - The Carter Sisters and Mother Maybelle, 1953
        Columbia 4-21138
      - He's Solid Gone - The Carter Sisters and Mother Maybelle, 1953
      - Flop-Eared Mule - Gid Tanner and His Skillet Lickers, circa 1956
        RCA Victor 447-0570
      - Soldier's Joy - Gid Tanner and His Skillet Lickers, circa 1956
      - Stony Fork - Ellis and Bill, The Green Mountain Boys, 1952
        RCA Victor 47-5087
      - Foggy Valley - Ellis and Bill, The Green Mountain Boys, 1952
      - Banjo Tunes and Songs - Pete Steele, 1958
        Folkways FS 3828
        - "Poor Ellen Smith"
        - "Little Birdie"
        - "Train A-Pullin' the Crooked Hill"
        - "Galilee"
          Lily Steele, vocals
        - "The Unclouded Days"
        - "Shady Grove"
        - "The Song of Hard Times"
          Performed by Lily Steele
        - "Goin' Around This World, Baby Mine"
        - "East Virginia"
        - "The Cuckoo"
        - "The War Is A-Ragin' for Johnny"
        - "Coal Creek March"
        - "Last Pay Day at Coal Creek"
        - "Ida Red"
        - "Pretty Polly"
        - "The Scoldin' Wife"
        - "The House Carpenter"
      - Wabash Cannon Ball - Roy Acuff, 1946
        Okeh 04466
      - The Hobo Song - Hobo Jack Turner, 1928
        Velvet Tone 1705-V
      - Hallelujah, I'm A Bum - Hobo Jack Turner, 1928
    - Side 2
      - Dubs from commercial recordings
        - "Country Boy Rock 'n Roll" - Don Reno and Red Smiley, 1959
          King 621
        - "What'll I Do With the Baby-O" - Grandpa Jones, 1959
          King 625
        - "Stay in the Wagon Yard" - Grandpa Jones, 1959
        - "Jennie Get the Hoe Cakes Done" - Grandpa Jones, 1959
        - "Fix Me a Pallet" - Grandpa Jones, 1959
        - "Black Snake Moan" - Blind Lemon Jefferson, 1956
          From Folkways FP 55. The date refers to the release of this particular LP.
        - "Misery Blues" - Ma Rainey, 1956
        - "Lord, I Just Can't Keep from Crying" - Blind Lemon Jefferson, 1956
        - "Eight More Miles to Louisville" - Grandpa Jones, 1957
          Decca 9-30264
        - "Knoxville Girl" - Louvin Brothers, 1959
          Capitol F4117
        - "Mrs. Jimmie Rodgers visits The Carter Family #1," 1956
          Acme 1010A
        - "Mrs. Jimmie Rodgers visits The Carter Family #2," 1956
          Acme 1010B
        - "Longing for Home" - The Carter Family, 1952
          Acme 991-A
        - "Climbing Zion's Hill" - The Carter Family, 1952
          Acme 991-B
        - "When the Sunset Turns the Ocean Blue to Gold" - The Carter Family, 1950
          Acme 1000-A
        - "Beyond the River" - The Carter Family, 1952
          Acme 1001-B
        - "Get in Line With God" - Lonnie Glosson, 1957
          Acme 1145-B
        - "The Old Dutchman's Prayer" - Lonnie Glosson, 1957
          Acme 1145-A
        - "Motherless Children" - The Carter Family, 1961
          Acme LP 1
        - "Wabash Cannonball" - The Carter Family, 1961
  - Hillbilly record dubs, live material by Scott Hambly, Neil V. Rosenberg and Rita Weill at KRE, AFC 2002/009: SR031
    - Sound recording, Tom Bebring, Berkeley (for the anthology); RXI 0143; 1 sound tape reel (Side 1: 00:32:00, Side 2: 00:32:03): analog, 7 1/2 and 3 3/4 ips, half track, mono; 7 in.; Digital files are available on request from the Folklife Reading Room.
      Due to a labeling issue, the digital file for Side 1 of the tape is identified as Side 2, and vice versa.
      Concordance note: The content of this recording is a near match for SR24 Redwood Canyon Ramblers collection (AFC 2011/011). SR24 has a recording not on SR031, from another (and unidentified) recording event.
      - Side 1
        - Hillbilly record dubs
          - "Time Clock Of Life" - Charlie Monroe, 1949
          - "Red Rocking Chair" - Charlie Monroe, 1949
          - "Jesus Met The Woman At The Well" - Pilgrim Travelers, 1950
          - "It Hurts Me Too" - Elmore James, 1965
          - "How I Miss My Darling Mother" - Don Reno, Red Smiley and the Tennessee Cutups, 1955
            King 1473
          - "Jesus Is Waiting" - Don Reno, Red Smiley and the Tennessee Cutups, 1954
          - "Black Jack David" - Cliff Carlisle, 1939
          - "Flag That Train" - Carlisle Brothers (Cliff and Bill), 1941
          - "Little Glass Of Wine" - Stanley Brothers, undated
            Rich-R-Tone
          - "I'm Goin' Up North," 1950
            East York School. The song is identified as "Satisfied" in Rosenberg's notes. From the LP Negro Folk Music of Alabama, vol. 1: Secular Music (Folkways).
          - "Little Sally Walker," 1950
            Lilly's Chapel School. From the LP Negro Folk Music of Alabama, vol. 1: Secular Music (Folkways).
          - "See See Rider"/"Satisfied," 1950
          - "Kansas City Blues," 1950
            "Red" Willie Smith. From the LP Negro Folk Music of Alabama, vol. 1: Secular Music (Folkways).
          - "Shady Grove/Cripple Creek," undated
            Fragment; possibly by Tom Bebring
      - Side 2
        - Live material by Scott Hambly, Neil V. Rosenberg and Rita Weill at Royal Recording Studio session (KRE), Berkeley, California, December 30, 1958
          Recorded by Tom Bebring. Hambly and Rosenberg talk occasionally between songs (and some songs are incomplete, or fragments). Instruments include guitar and kazoo. At one point Weill says she is not performing.
          Archivist's note: See AFC 2011/011: SR24 in the Redwood Canyon Ramblers collection for the same recording, but with the addition of "Shady Grove"/"Cripple Creek," believed to have been recorded at another session.
          - "Seems You're The Wrong Flavor In My Cream" - Neil Rosenberg
          - "Seems You're The Wrong Flavor In My Cream" - Neil Rosenberg with Scott Hambly accompanying
          - "Hanging Around The Skingame" - Neil Rosenberg
          - wine-spilling occurence
          - "Ella Speed" - picked by Neil Rosenberg
          - conversation about wine spiiling
          - "Ella Speed" - Neil Rosenberg and Scott Hambly singing
          - "12-Bar Blues" - Neil Rosenberg singing with Scott Hambly
          - "John Henry" - Neil Rosenberg
          - "Good Mornin' Blues" - Scott Hambly
          - "White House Blues" - Neil Rosenberg
      - Documentation
        - Song list and production notes for SR031, April 15, 2011, nvrsh1958-12-30.txt; 1 manuscript; black and white, digital (.txt)
  - Anthology of American Folk Music (Folkways), 1-39, 1952, AFC 2002/009: SR032; 1 sound tape reel (acetate, Side 1: 01:03:24, Side 2: 01:03:13): analog, 3 3/4 ips, half track, mono; 7 in.
    While 1952 is the date of the compilation, the recordings date from an earlier period.
  - Anthology of American Folk Music (Folkways), 40-84, 1952, AFC 2002/009: SR033; 1 sound tape reel (polyester, Side 1: 01:03:00, Side 2: 01:03:52): analog, 3 3/4 ips, half track, mono; 7 in.
    See the note for SR032.
  - Old-time singles, AFC 2002/009: SR034; D.K. Wilgus (first four songs); Guthrie T. Meade, Jr. (the balance of the songs); 1 sound tape reel (acetate; Side 1: 00:31:37, Side 2: 00:31:49): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in.
    - Side 1
      - "Pretty Polly" - B.F. Shelton, 1927
        VI 35838-3
        - "Pretty Polly" - Coon Creek Girls, 1938
          Vo 03659 C2247)
      - "Pretty Polly" - Frank Luther (assisted by Zora Layman and Leonard Stokes), 1938
        De 2140-B (63971); album 25-8
      - "Purty Polly" - John Hammond, 1925
        Ge 3021-4 (12197-B)
      - "Old Joe" - Humphrey Bate and His Possum Hunters, 1929
        Br 271
      - "My Wife Died Saturday Night" - Humphrey Bate and His Possum Hunters, 1929
      - "Hello Stranger" - The Carter Family, 1937
        De 5479
      - "Never Let the Devil Get the Upper Hand of You (Knoxville Girl)" - The Carter Family, 1937
      - "May Dearest May" - Bela Lam and His Greene County Singers, 1927
        OKeh 45136
      - "There's No One Like Mother to Me" - The Carter Family, 1936
        De 5242 B
      - "The Sporting Bachelors" - Buell Kazee, 1927
        Brunswick 157
    - Side 2
      - "Old Whisker Bill, the Moonshiner" - Buell Kazee, 1927
        Brunswick 145
      - "Rock Island (No Honey No)" - Buell Kazee, 1927
      - "There'll Be No Distinction There" - Blind Alfred and Orville Reed, 1927
        Vi 23550
      - "Beware" - Blind Alfred and Orville Reed, 1927
      - "Money Craving Folks" - Blind Alfred Reed, 1929
        Vi 40236
      - "Angeline, the Baker" - Uncle Eck Dunford, 1929
        Vi 40060
      - "Run Nigger Run" - Humphrey Bate and His Possum Hunters, 1929
        Br 275
      - "I've Got a Woman on Sourwood Mountain" - Earl Johnson, 1928
        possibly OKeh 45171 (the catalog number does not appear in the collection documentation)
      - "Johnnie Get Your Gun" - Earl Johnson, 1928
      - "How Can a Poor Man Stand Such Times and Live" - Blind Alfred Reed, 1930
      - "Fourth of July at the County Fair" - Bill Chitwood and His Georgia Mountaineers, 1927
        OKeh 45100
  - Old-time singles, AFC 2002/009: SR035; Guthrie T. Meade; 1 sound tape reel (acetate, Side 1: 00:26:17, Side 2: 00:31:54): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in.
    - Side 1
      - "Girl I Left Behind" - Buell Kazee, possibly 1958 or before
      - "Ain't Going to Lay My Armor Down" - McVay and Johnson, 1928
        Columbia 15370-D (147224)
      - "I'll Be Ready When the Bridegroom Comes" - McVay and Johnson, 1928
        Columbia 15370-D (147225)
      - "There'll Come a Time" - Charlie Poole and The North Carolina Ramblers, 1927
        Columbia 15116 (142657)
      - "Leaving Home" - Charlie Poole and The North Carolina Ramblers, 1927
        Columbia 15116 (146245)
      - "Bring Back My Blue-Eyed Boy To Me" - The Carter Family
        Victor 40190-B (49886)
      - "I Have No One to Love Me (But the Sailor on the Deep Blue Sea)" - The Carter Family
        His Master's Voice 184 (45030)
      - "Too Young to Get Married"/"Flatwood" - Crazy Hillbillies Band
        OKeh 45575 (152685)
      - "Bonaparte's Retreat" - Gid Tanner and His Skillet Lickers, 1929
        Columbia 15485-D (149280)
      - "Davy" - Weems String Band, 1928
        Columbia 15300-1 (145355)
    - Side 2
      - "Sunny Side of Life" - Blue Sky Boys, 1936
        Bluebird B-6457-A
      - "Where the Soul of Man Never Dies" - Blue Sky Boys, 1936
        Bluebird B-6457-B
      - "Deep Elem Blues" - Shelton Brothers, 1946
        Decca 46008-B C 9809)
      - "I've Got a Gal in Baltimore" - Georgia Crackers, 1928
        OKeh 45192 (81758)
      - "Stockade Blues" - Georgia Crackers, 1928
        OKeh 45192 (81761)
      - "Furniture Man" - Bill Chitwood and Bud Landress, 1925
        Brunswick 2884-A
      - "Johnny, Get Your Gun" - Bill Chitwood and Bud Landress, 1925
        Brunswick 2883-B
      - Two Black Crows, part 5 (Moran and Mack), 1928
        Columbia 1198-B (144975)
      - Two Black Crows, part 6 (Moran and Mack), 1928
  - Jim and Jesse 78s; Bill Monroe, AFC 2002/009: SR036; John Duffey; 1 sound tape reel (acetate; Side 1: 00:29:44, Side 2: 00:29:48) analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in.
    - Side 1
      - Jim and Jesse 78s
        - "Airmail Special," 1953
        - "Virginia Waltz," 1953
        - "A Memory of You," 1955
        - "Too Many Tears," 1955
        - "Are You Lost in Sin," 1954
        - "Look For Me," 1954
        - "Is It True," 1953
        - "My Darling's in Heaven," 1953
        - "I Will Always Be Waiting for You," 1953
        - "Purple Heart," 1953
        - "My Little Honeysuckle Rose," 1953
        - "Just Wondering Why," 1953
    - Side 2
      - Jim and Jesse 78s
        - "Are You Missing Me," 1952
        - "I'll Wash Your Love From My Heart," 1952
        - "I'll Wear the Banner," 1956
        - "My Garden of Love," 1956
        - "Sing, Sing, Sing," 1952
          Credited to The Virginia Trio
        - "Let Me Travel Alone," 1952
        - "God Put a Rainbow in the Cloud," 1952
        - "I'll Fly Away," 1952
        - "You Go to Your Church," circa 1962
        - "Just a Little Talk with Jesus," circa 1962
      - Bill Monroe
        - "Molly and Tenbrooks," 1949 or 1957
  - LPs: Mainer's Mountaineers; Newport Folk Festival, 1959 (selections); Folksong Festival at Carnegie Hall; New Lost City Ramblers, AFC 2002/009: SR037; 1 sound tape reel (polyester; Side 1: 00:32:41, Side 2: 00:32:05): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track; 7 in.
    - Side 1
      - Good Old Mountain Music - Mainer's Mountaineers, 1959
        Side 1 of the tape includes Side 1 and the first three songs from Side 2 of King K-666. Continued on Side 2.
        - "What'll I Do With the Baby-O"
        - "Workin' on a Buildin'"
        - "John Henry"
        - "Run Mountain"
        - "I'm Not Turning Backward"
        - "The Lonely Train"
        - "Pale Moonlight"
        - "Gathering Flowers from the Hillside"
        - "Shoot the Turkey Buzzard"
        - "Mother's Only Sleeping"
        - "Johnson County Blues"
    - Side 2
      - Good Old Mountain Music - Mainer's Mountaineers, 1959
        - "Big Ball's in Town"
        - "The Forks of the Road"
        - "The Yodelin' Mountaineer"
        - "I'll Remember You in My Prayers"
        - "Lonely Tombs"
      - Newport Folk Festival, vol. 3, 1959
        Vanguard VRS 9064. Hylo Brown, Clarence "Tater" Tate, and others perform with Earl Scruggs.
        - "Flint Hill Special" - Earl Scruggs
        - "Earl's Breakdown" - Earl Scruggs
        - "Cumberland Gap" - Earl Scruggs
        - "Lady Gay" - Frank Hamilton
      - Folk Song Festival at Carnegie Hall, 1959
        United Artists UAL 3050